# Adversary Emulation and SIEM Homelab

## Objective

This Wazuh Lab aimed to establish a controlled environment for simulating and detecting cyber attacks. The primary focus was to ingest and analyze logs within a Security Information and Event Management (SIEM) system, generating test telemetry to mimic real-world attack scenarios. This hands-on experience was designed to deepen understanding of network security, attack patterns, and defensive strategies.

### Skills Learned

- Advanced understanding of SIEM and XDR concepts and practical application.
- Proficiency in analyzing and interpreting network logs.
- Development of critical thinking and problem-solving skills in cybersecurity.
- Advanced understanding of Adversary Emulation and TTP’s with MITRE ATT&CK.

### Tools Used

- Wazuh as an SIEM.
- Ubuntu 22.04 Server for Wazuh.
- Windows 10 as Wazuh Agent Client.
- Ubuntu 22.04 Server as Wazuh Agent Client.
- Sysmon.
- Kali 2024.2 as Red team Operator.
- MITRE Caldera
- Wireshark.
## Construction

### Step 1:
Specifications:
CPU: 4 cores
RAM: 8GB+ 
HDD: 50+ GB
OS: Ubuntu 22.04 LTS

Download Ubuntu Server and after installation put in this command to install Wazuh Manager:

curl -sO https://packages.wazuh.com/4.8/wazuh-install.sh && sudo bash ./wazuh-install.sh -a with root rights.
Write down name, password and website after installation.

### Step 2:
Specifications:
CPU: 2 cores
RAM: 4GB
HDD: 50+ GB
OS: Windows 10 Pro

Install Win10 and Download Sysmon.
Download Wazuh Agent and install it with this command:

To deploy the Wazuh agent on your endpoint, edit the WAZUH_MANAGER variable to contain your Wazuh manager IP address or hostname.
.\wazuh-agent-4.8.1-1.msi /q WAZUH_MANAGER="10.0.0.2"
Login on Website and check connection.
Install Wireshark and other preferred Tools like Vscode or SysinternalSuite on Win10 Client.

### Step 3:
Specifications:
CPU: 2 cores
RAM: 4GB
HDD: 50+ GB
OS: Ubuntu 22.04 Server

Install the GPG key:
curl -s https://packages.wazuh.com/key/GPG-KEY-WAZUH | gpg --no-default-keyring --keyring gnupg-ring:/usr/share/keyrings/wazuh.gpg --import && chmod 644 /usr/share/keyrings/wazuh.gpg

Add the repository:
echo "deb [signed-by=/usr/share/keyrings/wazuh.gpg] https://packages.wazuh.com/4.x/apt/ stable main" | tee -a /etc/apt/sources.list.d/wazuh.list

Update the package information:
apt-get update

Install Wazuh Agent:
To deploy the Wazuh agent on your endpoint, edit the WAZUH_MANAGER variable to contain your Wazuh manager IP address or hostname.
WAZUH_MANAGER="10.0.0.2" apt-get install wazuh-agent

Enable services:
systemctl daemon-reload
systemctl enable wazuh-agent
systemctl start wazuh-agent
Login on Website and check connection.

### Step 4:
Specifications:
CPU: 4 cores
RAM: 8GB
HDD: 50+ GB
OS: Kali Linux 2024.2 

Create a Kali Linux VM and install MITRE Caldera with these commands:

git clone https://github.com/mitre/caldera.git --recursive
cd caldera
pip3 install -r requirements.txt
python3 server.py --insecure --build

Add Windows 10 and Ubuntu Server 22.04 as Agents over MITRE Caldera.
Commands to do that are in the “Agent” section from MITRE Caldera Dashboard. 
Check TTP’s and test attack pattern on the two target systems as you see fit.
